http://www.samuel-heath.com/privacy-policy

Privacy Policy
This privacy policy sets out how Samuel Heath and Sons plc uses and protects any information that you give Samuel Heath and Sons plc when you use this website.
Samuel Heath is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.
Samuel Heath may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from May 2018.
What we collect
We may collect the following information:
Identity information, including name and job title
Contact information including email address, phone number and postal address
Information such as preferences and interests relating to our different production collections for example bathroom fittings or door hardware
Purpose / Activity
Register you as a potential customer/influencer and carry out marketing and sales activity.
Type of Data:
Identity
Contact Details
Interest Preferences
Marketing and Communications
Basis for Processing:
Legitimate Interest
Purpose / Activity
Transact Business with you.
Type of Data:
Identity
Contact Details
Products Ordered and Purchased
Financial Transactional Information
Basis for Processing:
Legitimate Interest
Purpose / Activity
To administer and protect our business and our Website (including trouble shooting, data analysis, Testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data).
Type of Data:
Identity
Contact
Technical
Basis for Processing:
Legitimate Interest
Purpose / Activity
To use data analytics to improve our website, products & services, marketing, customer relationship and experiences.
Type of Data:
Technical
Usage
Basis for Processing:
Legitimate Interest
We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:
To improve our products and services.
Internal record keeping.
We may periodically send communications about new products, or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email or address which you have provided. You can opt out of this at any time by letting us know at the contacts below.
Information Storage
The data that we collect from you will be transferred to and stored at our head office in our customer management system. Access is password protected, with access restricted to designated staff.
Security
We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.
Links to other websites
Our website may contain links to other websites of interest primarily our pages on Instagram and other social media channels. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.
Controlling your personal information
You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:
Whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can tick to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for communication purposes.
If you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for communication purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to the Head of Data Security at the Head Office address.
We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we are required by law to do so.
You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the General Data Protection Act 2018. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to Samuel Heath and Sons plc, Leopold Street, Birmingham B12 0UJ for the attention of Head of Data Security.
If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
Right to be forgotten
We will hold your data whilst you continue to hold a relevant position and will update details as we become aware of any changes.
You may update information we hold at any time by contacting us.
Should you wish to stop us communicating to you, you may also do this by contacting us in writing to our office address, or through email at the details below.
We will act promptly and will mark your record as not to be contacted, but we will maintain the record so that we can ensure that you are not subsequently set up and contacted to again.
How we use cookies
A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.
We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.
Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.
You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.
Contact Details
Address:
Samuel Heath & Sons plc
Leopold Street
Birmingham
B12 0UJ
Contact:
Head of Data Security
Email:
datasecurity@samuel-heath.com
We think that you are in the
UK
Please choose your preferred location.
This is important because product specifications can be different in each location.
US
UK
